Gaining followers
and subscribers will change your life
forever as long as you do
it right.
I have nearly five million followers
across all social media accounts.
Growing all the accounts have transformed
my life.
I haven't had to go to work, so to speak,
since 2017, and I can work remote from
anywhere in the world.
And laying down on planes
is something I think we should all
aspire to do. The truth is
that getting 10,000 followers
is probably the
hardest part. Once you have 10,000,
it's not actually
that hard to take it to a
million.
Most people quit Brazilian jujitsu as a
white belt. Why?
Because it's the hardest
and you suck the most.
They say a black belt
is just a white belt that didn't give up.
I'm going to explain to you what I've
learned in all my time growing social
media
accounts. But before we get into it,
I think it's important you realize that it
took me four years of posting almost every
single day to reach 10,000
followers, and within four years of that,
I was at one million.
This is the compounding effect of social
media.
And I suppose quickly to understand the
compounding effect, let's quickly look at
the impact of doubling a penny.
If I said you could have a million dollars
today or
you could double a penny every day for 30
days, what would you pick?
Well,
if you were patient enough to compound the
penny over 30 days, you'd have
$5,368,709.12.
So even if you only grew your account by
5% a month, every month, that amount of
people is going to become larger every
time. That's the first lesson.
The onset will be the slowest,
the hardest, and you'll suck the most.
My first thing I'd say
is you need to really aim just to produce
100 videos as soon
as you can in the onset.
I have so many people who try
and overcomplicate the
process of growing an account.
I can teach you everything there
is to know about
audio, video setup, hooks, and pacing,
but so many of the lessons
that you need are
in the videos that do better than expected
and then the ones that bomb when you
expected them to do well.
It's the little improvements
that you make across time.
One of my favorite exercises for you
is to go find any of your favorite
YouTubers,
head to their videos, then click oldest.
If I go back 5, 10, or even 15 years,
it's incredible how awful the
level of content they used to produce is.
When we look at the realms of fitness,
we can work all year round for a pretty
insignificant gain in strength.
But we do it because we love the process.
However,
what you bench won't really impact your
life as much as running a proper
business.
When I look back at my favorite outcomes
from growing social media
accounts, it would be the times
that I upgraded my friends' flights to
business
class, or I bought my parents a Porsche,
and the fact that I'm aiming in the next
few years to try and take over all my
family's mortgage repayments.
My favorite thing to do
was to lie to my friends.
I'd ask what airline they're flying with,
and then I'd lie and say, "Oh, I'm
actually having a casual thing with an air
hostess that works for that airline.
Why don't you send me your booking
reference and I'll see what I can get.
Maybe an upgrade."
And then usually about $5,000 later,
I'd get an angry message
along the lines of,
"You shouldn't have done that."
But as soon as they're in
business class with a glass of champagne,
they forgive you pretty soon.
But we need to appreciate
that reaching 10,000 followers actually
does fucking
nothing for you.
But it's a milestone we need to work
tirelessly towards because
the lessons and experience of working
towards that milestone applies to email
marketing and all the other areas of your
business.
Right now, chances
are you're not good enough to do well on
social media, but in
time you can if you do the work.
For thousands of years before us,
never have we
had the opportunity to quite literally
retire our parents using our smartphones
and
some Wi-Fi, and you can.
Social media has also never been easier to
grow on.
It just takes one post to boot off
and your circumstances can change
massively.
So let's delve into some of the principles
essential to growing on
social media. One, problem-solving.
You should have an avatar, a person
that you want to help.
This is actually where a lot of people
that I work with make massive mistakes.
They think they want to help nurses get
fit, let's say.
I then tell them
that less than 1% of the world are nurses,
that most of them are
underpaid, fucking exhausted,
and looking to survive the week
and not get shredded
for a holiday to Cancun. I told
that person instead to focus on helping
exhausted
women regain control of their fitness
regimes.
Because let's be honest,
a mother of three children has many of the
same problems
as a nurse. Sleep, routine,
putting other people first.
It's important that we don't niche down
too far.
Instead of wanting to coach, I don't know,
CEOs to get fit, maybe aim for
high-functioning men
and women because there may be a
bricklayer who wants to lose
15 kilograms before Christmas who's put a
bet on with a tiler that he works with on
site, and to him,
that could be worth whatever it is
that you charge.
It's essential you don't niche down too
far because you're just making your life
so
much harder.
So make sure each post resonates with
that audience because if you
deliver 10 to 20 aha moments to someone,
they're going to start seeing you as
someone who understands their problems.
Now,
not everyone is going to want to hire you,
but maybe 5% to 10% of these
people are going to consider it.
So think about who it
is you want to work with.
Now write out their problems.
Now next to those, provide solutions
via content. Don't bunch these up either.
I hate it at the moment when people say,
"Here's five ways to have a better squat."
Like, shut up, you know it.
Just pick one and then blow my world away
with it
between 45 and 90 seconds.
Then you could do one piece of content
each for one
of those five principles, and boom,
that's nearly a week of content sorted.
As far as frequency, I think one a day
is a really good benchmark.
Number two, with every rep,
you will get better.
Every Olympian gold medalist once couldn't
do the thing they do.
They just got better at it to the point
that they're now world-class.
Even now,
you may think I'm some kind of
well-spoken, handsome geezer who
pronunciates and cleverly
and strategically plans his delivery of
these topics.
But the reality is I've just been doing
this a lot longer than you.
I've done more reps.
Same goes for jujitsu.
Most people I get beaten by have just done
it for longer than me.
So don't look for excuses.
It's not the market, it's not the economy,
it's the fact
you need to do more of this to get better
at this.
You want to be able to do more chin-ups,
do more chin-ups.
You want to be better at cooking,
cook more.
Want to get better at writing emails,
write more emails. You see the pattern.
Let's look at number three,
what I call my 20% rule.
I think you should be aiming for 20% of
the people who follow you to be on your
email list.
I have about 450,000 on mine at the
moment, and that's just for
one of my businesses. Collectively,
I have about 600,000 emails,
and I know that's
technically just over 10% of my following.
But for your smaller accounts, 20%
is the benchmark.
And if you said, "James,
you can lose your social media accounts
or your email
list," I'd keep the email list.
It's way more sacred, and this
is something I'll
teach you across time on this channel.
There are loads of ways to grow your email
list.
One of the ways is I like to cleverly link
a link in the description offering
something like, I don't know,
30 mind-blowing nuggets of wisdom to help
your brand
and business for free, which
are cleverly delivered at the same time
every day.
So check that out at the end of this video
and do it.
Just literally copy me,
because by the end of that automation,
you'll resonate with
the emotional journey necessary to compel
people to want to consider to do business
with you or don't.
Let's look at number four.
Be wary of a subprime audience.
I've been guilty many a time of trying to
go
viral because if you use skits
and trends to try and grow your audience,
you may
just grow a list of people
that just want to be entertained.
You don't want to bring in loads of vegans
if you own a butcher's.
Having a large audience
and not having many people within it on
your email list who
are in a position to buy your services
or offerings is like being a priest with a
14-inch cock. It looks good,
but what's the point?
You're better off growing an audience with
10,000 savages ready to go to war than
you are to have one million
that followed you because you cameoed two
episodes of
"Love Island." Number five,
your first one to three seconds
are everything.
So let's imagine you're making a topic on
short form, maybe even the topic of this
video. You could start with, "Hey, guys,
so when it comes to
wanting to grow your social media account
to 10,000 followers or more," that's
shit. Just think, maybe script,
maybe plan a little bit more.
If I had to grow my account to 10,000
followers again, I'd focus on doing X.
If you're someone with under 10,000
followers, it's essential
that you start Y.
Growing your social media account to
10,000 followers in 2024 is hard, but
if you
do it right, it's easy.
It's imperative that you--
Those first few seconds have to
really allow people to realize what it
is you are talking about
and how it can help
them. Which brings me on to number five.
Your content is not about you,
it's about them.
It's not about you, it's about them.
Even this channel, it's not about me,
it's about you.
Most coaches take pictures of their lunch
and their workout, and they wonder why
they have no clients and no business.
If you look through the video titles on
this channel, you'll notice that they're
all problems that people face.
I am subservient to your problems.
It's kind of what I do for a living.
I solve problems.
Fitness app,
people aren't accountable to their
training.
This business,
people don't know what they're doing on
social media.
Nutonic,
because necking four pills with a can of
White Monster isn't nice.
So whatever piece of content you post,
it's not about you, it's about them.
So when you plan a piece of content,
think about how it could genuinely change
their life forever. For instance,
there are two videos
that I can think of right
now, off the top of my head,
that changed my life forever.
I remember a post
that said a Romanian deadlift doesn't have
to touch the floor.
I never got lower back pain again.
Because in my mind, I thought I
was doing it
right, and that person knew where I
was at and what I could be doing wrong
because
he probably works with a lot of people.
Then I remember another.
Ed, my sensei on YouTube. I remember
when he said, "Make sure
that you plan your
titles and thumbnails before you hit
record on YouTube." Now, looking back,
those
two creators are in very different niches,
but they knew exactly who they were
talking to,
and they communicated something to me
that quite literally made me a
different person after I watched
that video.
So when you next plan out a piece of
content, ask yourself if it is really
life-changing.
Because a video of today's workout you
completed doesn't do shit for
me. That's the reason
that so many of your channels don't grow.
It's self-centered,
it's not well thought out,
it's not problem-solving.
And the biggest thing I see with creators
trying to work their way to 10,000
followers is this.
You massively overestimate what can be
done in weeks, but you,
at the same time,
massively underestimate what can be done
in months and years.
Now,
the sixth bit of advice for growing your
channel isn't actually something you
should do,
it's something you absolutely shouldn't
do.
There is one thing that
is absolutely destroying creators'
retention.
It's filling their audience with a
subprime type of follower, and
if they could
only stop doing this thing,
they'd have so much of an easier time
growing their
channel.
And if you want to know what you need to
stop doing, well, you need to
watch this video here.
It's only eight minutes long and, well,
it will change the
way you see social media forever